icfi.com 2017-02-04

# » ICF

Effective Date: September 20, 2016

* * *

### Scope

This Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”) applies to the webpages, intranet pages, mobile applications, features, widgets, online services, electronic mail, and related content (collectively, the “Site(s)") owned, operated, or controlled by ICF International, Inc. and its affiliates, subsidiaries, trusted business partners or alliances, agents, subcontractors, or third-party vendors (collectively, "ICF" or which may be referred to as “we”, “us”, and “our”), as well as any information ICF collects offline in connection with our services or programs.

ICF is a privacy conscious organization and your trust is paramount to us. This Privacy Statement discloses our information treatment practices, from what type of information we gather and track about Site users to how we collect, use, process, share, or transfer such information. This Privacy Statement also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your information. This Privacy Statement does not apply to any site that does not display or link to this Privacy Statement or that has its own privacy statement. This Privacy Statement does not apply to instances where we merely process data on our client’s behalf for their benefit unless as otherwise expressed in writing. We encourage you to read this Privacy Statement for this Site, privacy statements for our other Sites where this Privacy Statement may not apply (e.g., European Economic Areas (“EEA”), etc.), or applicable privacy statement for other sites you visit or review.

By accessing or continuing to use this Site, you consent to the information collection, use, and disclosure practices described in this Privacy Statement and to the content of our Terms of Use. Unless otherwise expressly stated and to the extent permissible by law, if you reside outside the United States and continue to use our Sites, you understand and agree that your information may be processed in the United States where laws regarding processing of information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

This Privacy Statement may be supplemented or amended from time to time at our discretion. When we make such changes to this Privacy Statement, will adhere to Notification of Privacy Statement Changes’ below. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement. By accessing or continuing to use our Sites after we post any such changes, you consent to accept this Privacy Statement as modified.

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement or you want to let us know about our Site or marketing permissions, please Contact Us.

* * *

### Table of Contents

  * Personal Information Types We Collect
  * Collection of Personal Information
    1. Information You Voluntarily Provide to Us
    2. Information Collected Automatically
  * Use of Personal Information
    1. Marketing
    2. ICF's Contracted Third-Party Websites
    3. Job Applicant Data
    4. Information for Suppliers and Strategic Alliances
    5. Personal Information Disclosure and International Transfers
  * Disclaimers
    1. Legal Disclosure 
    2. Public Forums
    3. Linking to Non-ICF Websites and Third Party Applications
  * Personal Information Accuracy, Privacy, and Security
  * Cookies, Web Beacon, and Other Technology
    1. Cookies
    2. Web Beacons and Other Technologies
  * Notification of Privacy Statement Changes
  * Retention
  * Children's Online Privacy Protection
  * Your Rights
  * Privacy Questions and Access

* * *

### Personal Information Types We Collect

We collect information that identifies you as a specific individual (e.g., our workers, candidates, suppliers, business contacts and Website users) and can be used to contact or identify you. This information may consist of, but is not limited to, your name, current job title, occupation company address, postal address, email address, telephone number, or any other information required to provide our services and programs or to carry out a transaction you have requested (collectively “Personal Information”). We will always try to give individuals appropriate notice of what data will be collected and how it will be used. We only will process that data if we consider it fair and lawful to do so. 

### Collection of Personal Information

Information is collected in two ways:

  1. Information You Voluntarily Provide to Us 
  2. Information Collected Automatically 

  1. **INFORMATION YOU VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE TO US**  
You may choose to give us Personal Information directly in a variety of situations. For example, you may give us your Personal Information by:   

    * submitting an online or contact form through our Sites; 
    * sending an email to us requesting information; 
    * signing up for a mailing list; 
    * registering for an event;
    * submitting a comment on a related blog; 
    * downloading a white paper;
    * following a link from an ICF email address to a feature on one of our Sites; or 
    * participating, in connection with a job application or inquiry, whether advertised on ICF Sites or otherwise, in ICF employee recruitment process. 
If we collect Personal Information from you at any other time on our Sites, we will either link to this Privacy Statement, link to our other applicable privacy statements, or state that Personal Information is being collected at that time and it is always a voluntary submission. Due to the open nature of the Internet, ICF requests that you do not send us unsolicited proprietary or other confidential information through our Sites.
  2. **INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY**  
We also may collect information through the use of various technologies to enhance your experience on the Site. For example, when you visit our Sites, we may automatically log certain information that your browser sends us, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring website addresses (“Automated Non-Identifiable Data”). We may collect information about the pages you view within our Sites and other actions you take while visiting us. We may use such technologies to determine whether you've opened an e-mail or clicked on a link contained in an e-mail. For details regarding the technologies we employ, see Cookies, Web Beacon and Other Technologies below. 

### Use of Personal Information

We may use your Personal Information to: 

  * communicate with you; 
  * process an order;
  * contact you via surveys to conduct research;
  * register you for a service or program;
  * facilitate your participation in your requested private or public forum end you direct mail, email, or telephone contact from us. Please be aware that when you voluntarily make your Personal Information available for viewing by third parties online, such as on a blog or public message board, your information can be viewed, collected, and used by individuals and companies outside of ICF. ICF is not responsible for any unauthorized third-party use of such information that is provided in a public forum; 
  * address your inquiry or consider you for employment purposes;
  * customize your view of the Site in a registration-based area or to tailor information you receive from us;
  * facilitate you conducting business with us if you are a supplier or a business partner;
  * protect the rights or property of ICF, our business partners, suppliers, clients, or others when we have reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or could be affected; or
  * disclose your Personal Information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, or the rights of others, or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web sites

ICF and its trusted business partners, agents, subcontractors, or third-party vendors only uses Personal Information for purposes consistent with this Privacy Statement. 

  1. **Marketing**  
The information you provide to us, as well as the information we have collected about you indirectly, may be used by us for marketing purposes. Before we do so, however, we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether or not to have your information used in this way.
  2. **ICF's Contracted Third-Party Websites**  
ICF contracts with a number of third-party vendors to enhance your experience on our Sites and provide special features, such as online payment processing, online job applications, and investor materials. All such third-party vendors are prohibited from using your Personal Information except to provide these services to ICF, and we require them to maintain the confidentiality of your information. In addition, these third-party vendors are subject to contractual prohibitions on selling or sharing any Personal Information. The [Investor section](http://investor.icf.com/ "View the Investor Relations section") is hosted by Thomson Reuters. You can [access Thomson Reuters' Terms of Use for Interactive Data](http://www.interactivedata.com/index.php/Contents/show/content/quoteTerms "Thomson Reuters' Terms of Use"). The Career Opportunities section (or Career Center) is hosted by Taleo. You can [access Taleo's Privacy Policy](http://www.taleo.com/privacy/privacy-policy "Access Taleo's Privacy Policy"). Also see Cookies, Web Beacon and Other Technologies below for information on how these third-party sites may be using cookies.
  3. **Job Applicant Data**  
If candidates visit and submit their Personal Information through the third-party website that facilitates ICF’s Career Center, we may use such information for recruiting-related purposes. See "ICF's Contracted Third-Party Websites" above for more information. We may use cookies and other tracking technology to provide applicants with a personalized online experience, to send relevant information about careers and opportunities at ICF, and to analyze the effectiveness of our recruitment efforts and resources. More information about how we may use applicants’ data may be found below in Cookies, Web Beacon and Other Technologies.

When we disclose information to a third party, for example, to check a reference or obtain a background check, we will inform you beforehand and receive your prior written consent. ICF Human Resources also will provide additional related information during the recruitment process. Unless you tell us not to do so, ICF Human Resources will retain your Personal Information and other data for future consideration in accordance with the Retention section below. We also retain non-personally identifiable statistical information about applicants.

  4. **Information for Suppliers and Strategic Alliances**  
If you are an ICF supplier or strategic alliance and visit our Site, we may use the information provided on our Site in connection with entering into or performing a transaction with you. For example, this may include sharing information with other parts of ICF, ICF's business partners or alliances, clients, financial institutions and postal or government authorities involved in fulfillment (subject to any confidentiality obligations that may exist). It also may be used to administer and develop our relationship with you.
  5. **Personal Information Disclosure and International Transfers**  
ICF is a global organization with business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. As such, we may share information about you within ICF and transfer it to countries in the world where we conduct business in connection with the uses identified in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Our Privacy Statement and our practices are designed to provide a globally consistent level of protection for Personal Information all over the world. This means that even in countries whose laws provide for less protection for your information, we will still handle your information in the manner described here. 

In some cases, ICF uses trusted suppliers located in various countries to collect, use, analyze, and otherwise process information on our behalf. It is our practice to require such suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Statement and our policies.

From time to time, we may disclose information that identifies you at an individual level and which we collected on our Site to other non-ICF entities that are not acting as our suppliers, such as our business partners or alliances. Except as described in this Privacy Statement, we only will do so with your prior consent.

ICF regards its databases, which may include your Personal Information, as a valuable asset. Circumstances may arise where, whether for strategic or other business reasons, ICF decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in some countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of Personal Information or the sale or transfer of such databases of Personal Information to prospective or actual purchasers, or the receipt of such information from sellers. It is our practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions. With the exception of such sale or transfer, we do not sell or lease Personal Information.

### Disclaimers

  1. **Legal Disclosure**  
Please be aware that in certain circumstances, your Personal Information may be subject to disclosure to government agencies pursuant to judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process. We also may share your information to protect the rights or property of ICF, our business partners or alliances, suppliers or clients, and others when we have reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or could be affected.

ICF will disclose Personal Information or the content of an email message, without notice, to law enforcement, government officials, or other investigative personnel if we determine it is required to do so by law. ICF also may disclose such information based on its good faith belief that such action is necessary to: 

    * Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on ICF; 
    * Protect and defend the rights or property of ICF or enforce our Terms of Use; or 
    * Act under exigent circumstances to protect the rights, property, or safety of users of our Sites, the public, or ICF.
  2. **Public Forums**  
When you voluntarily make your Personal Information available for viewing by third parties online, such as on a blog or public message board, your information can be viewed, collected, and used by individuals and companies outside of ICF. ICF is not responsible for any unauthorized third-party use of such information that is provided in a public forum.
  3. **Linking to Non-ICF Websites and Third Party Applications**  
To allow you to interact with other websites on which you may have accounts (such as Facebook and other social media sites) or join communities on such sites, we may provide links or embed third-party applications that allow you to login, post content, or join communities from our Sites. We provide links to other websites for your convenience and for informational purposes only. ICF is not responsible for the content, accuracy of, or cookies set by any third-party linked site that is not operated by or on behalf of ICF or for any other links contained in such third-party sites. The inclusion of any link to a website not owned by ICF is not an endorsement by ICF of the site or its contents or accuracy and does not suggest that the opinions expressed on a third-party site are representative of the views or opinions of ICF. You may wish to review the privacy statements in use on third-party sites before interacting with such third-party websites.

ICF assumes no responsibility for any links to our Sites from another party's website. You may post a link to any portion of the Site without prior written permission. However, any such links must not use framing techniques or in any way represent the Site or its content as being connected with another organization. In addition, you may not use any meta tags or hidden text in your website that incorporate the ICF name or the names of any ICF affiliate, subsidiary, business, program, or service.

### Personal Information Accuracy, Privacy, and Security

We intend to maintain Personal Information accuracy, completeness current status, and security. In the event of changes in your Personal Information, you may inform us to make sure that our information is up-to-date.

We implement commercially reasonable physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help us protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of your Personal Information and prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorized access, unauthorized interception, or information alteration. For example, ICF takes appropriate measure to make sure that the Personal Information you provide is stored on computer servers in controlled, secure environments.

In some instances, ICF contracts with third-party vendors for website hosting and data storage, including Personal Information. These third-party vendors are required to implement security measures and are subject to contractual prohibitions on selling or sharing any Personal Information. When Personal Information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

Your choice to disclose Personal Information in an email submission or online form is voluntary. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or warranty the security of any such Personal Information or fully ensure that your private communications and other Personal Information will not be inadvertently disclosed to third parties by ICF or its business partners, agents, subcontractors, or other third-party vendors. Although we take commercially reasonable precautions to maintain the security of our Sites and servers, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications.

### Cookies, Web Beacon, and Other Technology

As mentioned above, we collect information from your visits to our Sites to help us gather statistics about usage and effectiveness, personalize your experience, and tailor our interactions with you. We do so through the use of various automated technologies, including scripts, tags, Local Shared Objects (Flash cookies), Local Storage (HTML5) beacons, and one most commonly used called "cookies" that over time provide valuable insight to help improve your experience as a visitor or user.

  1. **Cookies**  
Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. However, by remembering you and your preferences, for example, you don’t have to give the same information, such as a username/password or registration form, again during your session or on subsequent visits to our Sites. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognize a user’s device. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to experience fully the Sites you visit. 

ICF studies Automated Non-Identifiable Data in our Internet access logs at both an aggregate and individual level to help us tailor content toward your interests and needs. For instance, to determine the usefulness of a particular Site feature, we may analyze collective traffic to a portion of our Sites. This collective data contains no Personal Information and is used to help us operate and enhance our Sites and services. Some of our business partners, such as Taleo and Thomson Reuters, also use cookies when you interact with sections of the Sites, which are hosted by these third-party vendors. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

Cookies perform many different jobs. Some are "necessary" because they are required to make the website perform properly. Other cookies are "functional" and are used to improve the way the website functions for you. The majority of our cookies are "first-party," meaning that they are set by the same website where they are read. Third-party cookies are set and read by contracted vendors that provide services to ICF, such as web analytics or online advertising. A list of cookies on our Sites and the purposes for which such cookies are used are set out below. By using our Sites, you agree that we can place cookies and other similar technologies on your device as explained below. Please bear in mind that current “Do Not Track” initiatives are not recognized by our Sites. Please, however, follow the steps under the below Your Rights section if you would like to decline cookies. If you have any queries about these cookies or would like more information about them, please Contact Us.

Originating Domain

| 

Name 

| 

Expiration

| 

Purpose  
  
---|---|---|---  
icf.com  
icfi.com/china  
icfi.com/canada | ASP.NET_SessionId  | Session  | This necessary cookie is automatically created by ASP.NET—the web application framework that runs the website—and holds a unique value that is used to identify your return visits.   
icf.com  | SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE  | 1 Year  | This necessary cookie is automatically created by the Sitecore Content Management System (CMS) and holds a unique value that is used to identify your return visits.   
icf.com  | SC_ANALYTICS_SESSION_COOKIE  | Session  | This necessary cookie is automatically created by the Sitecore Content Management System (CMS) to remember your activity during a single visit to the site. This includes pages you've visited and the date and time you visited them.   
  
icf.com  
ecommerceaccel.com  
blog.ecommerceaccel.com  
highlights.icf.com  
investor.icf.com  
media.icfi.com  
products.icfi.com  
icfithinking.com  
mostra.com  
citytechinc.com  
olson.com  
olson1to1.com  
olsonengage.com  
ca.olson.com  
pulsepointgroup.com

| 

_ga  
_gat  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmx  
_utmxx  
_utmz

| Up to 2 years  | These third-party Google Analytics cookies are used to collect nonpersonally identifiable information about how you use the website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, how visitors arrived at the site, and pages visited. Learn more about the privacy and security of Google Analytics data at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.   
icf.com | cuvid | 2 years from set/update | This cookie is set by the Click Dimensions tracking script and is used to determine unique visitors to the site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that the application uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure. Learn more about Click Dimensions web analytics cookies at: <http://help.clickdimensions.com/clickdimensions-cookies-for-web-analytics/>.  
icf.com | cusid | 30 minutes from set/update | This cookie is set by the Click Dimensions tracking script and is used to establish and continue a user session with the site. Learn more about Click Dimensions web analytics cookies at: <http://help.clickdimensions.com/clickdimensions-cookies-for-web-analytics/>.  
icf.com | cuvon | 30 minutes from set/update | This cookie is set by the Click Dimensions tracking script and is used to signal the last time a visitor viewed a page. Learn more about Click Dimensions web analytics cookies at: <http://help.clickdimensions.com/clickdimensions-cookies-for-web-analytics/>.  
icf.com  | icfi  | 90 days  | If you check the "Remember Me" checkbox on any of our forms, the information entered into the form (name, email, phone, etc.) will be stored in this functional cookie for your convenience so that you will not have to enter the information again.   
icf.com.br  
| ASPSESSIONIDQSBQARCT  
| Session  | This necessary cookie is automatically created by Classic ASP, the web application framework that runs these websites. This cookie holds a unique value that is used to identify your return visits.   
jobs.icfi.com  
(icfi.taleo.net)  | lastFollowedLinkId  
JSESSIONID  | Session  | These first-party cookies are automatically set by Taleo's web application, which powers ICF's job applicant system in the Careers Opportunities section. They are used to identify your return visits and click paths.   
icf.com—only used on forms with paid registration  | smSessionID  | Session  | This functional cookie is used to validate each step within the registration and payment process and retrieve previously entered data.   
icf.com  | homepagealert_xxx  
(name changes)  
| 30 days  | This functional cookie is set when you dismiss the alert message that may appear underneath the primary image on the homepage so as not to continue displaying the message when you return to the homepage.   
icf.com | CartID | 7 days | This secure functional cookie is set when you add products to your shopping cart on ICFi.com. Its primary purpose is to persist your order across multiple visits to the website. No personally identifiable information is stored within the cookie.  
icf.com  
icfithinking.com  
google.com | __gads  
NID  
PREF  
OGPC | 2 years | 

These third-party Google Analytics cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how you use icfi.com when coming from an online ad provided by Resonate Networks. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the effectiveness of advertising.   
  
icf.com  
technologyforgreat.com  
| pid | Up to 2 years | 

This cookie is generated by the Twitter widgets and buttons and is used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about Twitter's privacy policy at: <https://twitter.com/privacy>.  
  
mostra.com | PHPSESSID | Session | 

This cookie is generated by the PHP web framework and is used to hold a unique value that identifies current and returning visitors to the site.  
  
google.com | GAPS   
HSID  
SSID  
APISID  
SAPISID  
ACCOUNT_CHOOSER  
LSID  
BEAT  
SID  
| Up to 2 years | 

These cookies are used on citytechinc.com by Google to track usage of their products and services including Google Maps, Google Calendar, Google Translate, Google Docs and YouTube. More information about Google's privacy policy at: <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>.   
  
google.com | NID  
NSID  | 6 months | 

These cookies are used on citytechinc.com by Google to track usage of their products and services including Google Maps, Google Calendar, Google Translate, Google Docs and YouTube. More information about Google's privacy policy at: <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>.   
  
google.com | GoogleAccountsLocale_session  | Session | 

These cookies are used on citytechinc.com by Google to track usage of their products and services including Google Maps, Google Calendar, Google Translate, Google Docs and YouTube. More information about Google's privacy policy at: <http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>.   
  
investor.icf.com  | CP  | Session  | This first-party cookie is automatically set by Thomson Reuters, which hosts the Investor Relations section of icfi.com. The cookie holds a unique value that remembers your activity during a single visit to the site.  
products.icfi.com | SESS | 20 days | This necessary cookie is automatically generated by the Drupal system and is used to hold a unique value that identifies current and returning visitors to the site.  
products.icfi.com | has_js | Session | 

This functional cookie is used to alter the system behavior depending on whether you have JavaScript enabled in your browser.  
  
quantserve.com | mc | Up to 2 years | 

This third-party cookie is used by the TypePad blogging platform on our [http://icfithinking.com](http://icfithinking.com/) blog for advertising purposes. To learn more about TypePad's use of cookies, visit: <http://www.typepad.com/privacy>.  
  
scorecardresearch.com | UID  
UIDR | Up to 2 years | 

These third-party cookies are used by ShareThis to provide buttons that help share articles on our TypePad-powered blog, [http://icfithinking.com](http://icfithinking.com/). ShareThis makes use of Scorecard Research tracking, which sets the UID and UIDR cookies. To learn more about ShareThis' use of cookies, visit: <http://sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
icfithinking.com | __qca | Up to 2 years | 

This third-party cookie is set by the TypePad blogging platform and is used to collect anonymous information about how you use [http://icfithinking.com](http://icfithinking.com/) when coming from an online ad provided by Quantcast. To learn more about TypePad's use of cookies, visit: <http://www.typepad.com/privacy>.  
  
olson1to1.com  
olsonengage.com | s_vnum  
s_ev11  
s_fid  
s_dl  
gpv_pn  
s_invisit  
s_nr  
s_lv  
s_lv_s | Up to 5 years | These third-party Adobe Site Catalyst cookies are used to collect nonpersonally identifiable information about how you use the website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, how visitors arrived at the site, and pages visited.  
olson1to1.com  
olsonengage.com | s_sq  
s_cc | Session | These third-party Adobe Site Catalyst cookies are used to collect nonpersonally identifiable information about how you use the website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, how visitors arrived at the site, and pages visited.  
olson.com  
olson1to1.com  
ca.olson.com | balanceid | Session | This necessary cookie is automatically created by network infrastructure, which balances the load of web traffic to increase performance and load times.  
pulsepointgroup.com | has_js | Session | This cookie is used by [http://pulsepointgroup.com](http://pulsepointgroup.com/) site's JavaScript to enable styling and enhanced user experience.  
linkedin.com | X-LI-IDC | Session | 

This cookie is generated by the LinkedIn share and follow buttons and is used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about LinkedIn's cookie policy at: <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>  
  
linkedin.com | bcookie | Up to 2 years | 

This cookie is generated by the LinkedIn share and follow buttons and is used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about LinkedIn's cookie policy at: <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>  
  
linkedin.com | lidc | 24 hours | 

This cookie is generated by the LinkedIn share and follow buttons and is used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about LinkedIn's cookie policy at: <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>  
  
sharethis.com | __unam | 9 months | 

This cookie is used on citytechinc.com and is generated by ShareThis which facilitates the easy sharing of pages/links. It is used to track which pages you visit and activity. More information about ShareThis' privacy policy at: <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
sharethis.com | __stid  
__uset  | Session | 

This cookie is used on citytechinc.com and is  generated by ShareThis which facilitates the easy sharing of pages/links. It is used to track which pages you visit and activity. More information about ShareThis' privacy policy at: <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
sharethis.com | __stdlxmap  
__stgmap  | 1 week | 

This cookie is used on citytechinc.com and is generated by ShareThis which facilitates the easy sharing of pages/links. It is used to track which pages you visit and activity. More information about ShareThis' privacy policy at: <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
sharethis.com | user_segment  | 1 month | 

This cookie is used on citytechinc.com and is generated by ShareThis which facilitates the easy sharing of pages/links. It is used to track which pages you visit and activity. More information about ShareThis' privacy policy at: <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
sharethis.com | user_segment  | 1 month  | 

This cookie is used on citytechinc.com and is generated by ShareThis which facilitates the easy sharing of pages/links. It is used to track which pages you visit and activity. More information about ShareThis' privacy policy at: <http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>.  
  
twitter.com

| _twitter_sess  
guest_id  
tz_offset_sec  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz  
_utmv  
| Session | 

These cookies are generated by the Twitter share and follow buttons and are used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about Twitter's cookie policy at: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514>.  
  
twitter.com

| external_referer | 24 hours | This cookie is generated by the Twitter share button and is used to track which pages you visit. Learn more about Twitter's cookie policy at: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514>.  
  
youtube.com

| VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  | Up to 1 year | 

This cookie is generated by the YouTube share button and attempts to estimate your bandwidth. Learn more about YouTube's cookie policy at: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  
  
youtube.com

| YSC  | Session | 

This cookie is generated by the YouTube share button and attempts to estimate your bandwidth. Learn more about YouTube's cookie policy at: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  
  
youtube.com

| PREF | Session | 

This cookie is generated by the YouTube share button and stores session preferences that relate to your activity when watching the embedded videos. Learn more about YouTube's cookie policy at: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  

  2. **Web beacons and other technologies**  
We also may include Web beacons (including conversion pixels) or other technologies in marketing e-mail messages or our newsletters to determine whether you have opened messages, clicked links, or implemented similar actions. Web beacons do not place information on your device, but may work in conjunction with cookies to monitor website activity and the information on cookies above also applies to Web beacons and similar technologies. Conversion pixels are small codes located on a particular Web page which are triggered when someone visits a page resulting in an increase in the conversion count. 

Please bear in mind that you cannot remove or block Web beacons or personalized URLs, as they form part of the content of Web pages and emails rather than placing information on your device. But, as they work in conjunction with cookies, turning off cookies also will prevent any Web beacons from tracking your user activity on our Sites. Web beacons will still account for an anonymous visit, but your unique information will not be recorded.

Some of our business partners or alliances set Web beacons and cookies on our Sites. In addition, third-party social media buttons may log certain information such as your IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring website addresses, and, if you are logged in to those social media sites, they may also link such collected information with your profile information on that site. We do not control third party tracking technologies.

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

As we noted above, we may, from time to time, amend this Privacy Statement. The “Effective Date” reference at the top of this page indicates when we last revised this Privacy Statement, and any changes to this Privacy Statement will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Statement on our Sites. Your continued use of our Sites or engagement in the Interactions after we implement such changes also will constitute your affirmative consent to the revised Privacy Statement. 

### Retention

We will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to fulfill your requests or inquiries, provide services, or comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Personal Information about unsuccessful candidates/applicants will be held for 12 months following submission in the U.S., Canada, and Brazil, and for 6 months in Europe and Asia.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection

ICF is committed to protecting children's privacy online. Our Sites are not intentionally designed for or directed at children under the age of 13. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), ICF will not intentionally collect, maintain, or distribute information about anyone under 13 years of age. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received Personal Information from a user under the age of 13, we will delete these data from our records.

### Your Rights

U.S. Domestic and International Residents

**General**. You may, at any time, exercise your right to decline to supply certain information while using our Sites. Please bear in mind that you, however, may not be able to access certain content or participate in some features on our Sites. If you tell us that you do not want us to use your information to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your request, we will respect your wishes. You are entitled to know whether we hold Personal Information about you and, if we do, to have access to that Personal Information and require it to be corrected if it is inaccurate. We generally do not make decisions by purely automatic means, but if we do, you have the right to object. If we are going to use your Personal Information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we can use your Personal Information in such a way. 

**Marketing**. You may, at any time, exercise your right to prevent us from sharing marketing materials with you by checking certain boxes on our forms, utilizing the unsubscribe or opt-opt mechanisms in the emails we send you, indicating so when we call you, or Contacting Us. In such cases, we will retain minimum Personal Information to note that you opted out in order to avoid contacting you again.

If you have subscribed to one or more of our newsletters or receive information from ICF via email or postal mail and would like to modify or cancel these mailings, please follow the instructions in the mailing, send an email to [info@icf.com](mailto:info@icf.com), or use the Contact Us form on our Sites. For best results, please forward a copy of the mailing you received from ICF. 

**Cookies**. If you want to remove existing cookies from your device, you can implement those steps by using your browser options. If you want to block future cookies being placed on your device, you can change your browser settings to do this. When you review your browser settings or options, you can identify the ICF cookies in the name. Unless you have adjusted your browser settings to block cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our Sites or click a link in a targeted email we have sent you, even if you have previously deleted our cookies. Please bear in mind that deleting and blocking cookies will have an impact on your user experience as parts of the Site may no longer work. For more information on managing cookies, see [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies "Managing Cookies").

**California Residents**. California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our Site visitors who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, details about their Personal Information (if any) that we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of Personal Information that were shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year.

**EEA and Switzerland Residents**. If your data was originally collected in Europe (the European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland) and it is transferred from an ICF entity Europe to an ICF entity outside Europe, you have the following additional rights:

  * to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection authority and/ or to take action through a court to enforce compliance by ICF with the terms of the Privacy Statement,
  * to obtain a copy of our Data Protection Policy upon request, and
  * to make complaints to, obtain appropriate redress and, where appropriate, receive compensation from the ICF entity within Europe that originally obtained and processed your Personal Information, in respect of any damage suffered by you as a result of a breach of the Privacy Statement by any other ICF entity to which the Personal Information may have been transferred.

### Privacy Questions and Access

You can exercise any of your rights by Contacting Us or submitting any requests regarding exercising your rights in writing to: 

**ATTN: Dan Smith  
Online Data Privacy Manager  
ICF  
9300 Lee Highway  
Fairfax, VA 22031-1207 USA  
E-mail: [info@icf.com](mailto:info@icf.com)  
Please note that you may be required to prove your identity before we can fulfill your request**.

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Statement or our Sites and email marketing practices, please use any of the above contact means.

**Please note that no permission is granted for you to use ICF's logo, icons, or content. You must obtain our prior written permission to post additional graphic or textual material along with your link to our Sites**.
